Guide to the Bobbye S. Ortiz Papers, 1919-1993 and undated (bulk 1950-1990) RL.00978
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Phonograph Records Series, [195-]-[198-] and undated
  - Ten Inch Recordings
    - Peru (Box 48)
      - #232 Title: Music of Peru: Ethnic Folkways Library (Box 48)
        Album 3: Los Jilacatas (Aymara dance), Sonccuiman (Quechua yaravi)
        Album 4: Chunguinada (Mestizo dance), Torovelakuy (Mestizo toril), Wakrapukara (Quechua dance), Collaguas (Aymara dance)
        Record Label: Folkways Records, 01452, 01453, 01454, 01455
    - Russia
      - #233 Title: Moscow Strikes Back
        - Performer: Gabt USSR (Box 48)
          Album 1: Strolling Home, By the Village
          Album 2: Do Not Touch Us, Life is Better
          Album 3: March of the Tanks, Songs of My Native Land
          Record Label: Stinson Trading Co., 6366/9316/9320
    - Spain
      - #234 Title: Quelli quelli quer, Sevillanos (Cruz de Maya)
        - Performer: (released through the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Bridge) (Box 48)
          Record Label: Disc New York, 6047
      - #235 Title: Road to Aviles, Santa Espina
        - Performer: (released through the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Bridge) (Box 48)
          Record Label: Disc New York, 6046
      - #236 Title: El tragala (siglo XIX), El paso del Ebro (Canciones populares de la guerra de independencia de Espaa)
        - Performer: Gustavo Pittaluga, Rodolfo Halffter (Box 48)
          Record Label: La Voz de Espaa, 1001
      - #237 Title: Canciones populares de la guerra de independencia de Espaa
        - Performer: Euzko-Gudari, Rodolfo Halffter, Gustavo Pittaluga, El vino duce, Marineros (Box 48)
          Record Label: La Voz de Espaa, 1005
    - United States
      - #238 Title: This Train, Bring Back Those Happy Days
        - Performer: Sister Rosetta Tharpe (Box 48)
          Record Label: Decca, 2558
  - 45 RPM Recordings
    - Argentina (Box 49)
      - #239 Title: Rcital du guitariste
        - Performer: Atahualpa Yupanqui: sur des thmes du folklore Indien d'Argentine (Box 49)
          Vidala, Pastorale Indienne, Baguala, Malambo, Duerme, duerme, negrito
          Record Label: BAM, LD301
    - Brazil
      - #240 Title: Cano do metalrgico
        - Performer: Manoel Costa (Box 49)
          Cano do metalrgico, Trem do horror, P de meia, Sugestes
          Record Label: Auan Promoes Fonograficas, CGC: 49.917.909/0001-06
    - Cuba
      - #241 Title: Como Tin Tin, Sin misterio, Se fundio el bombillo, Macabi
        - Performer: Hermanos Bravo (Box 49)
          Record Label: EGREM, Dujo: Curva RIAA, EPD-4028
      - #242 Title: Carta del Che leda por Fidel
        - Performer: Fidel Castro (Box 49)
          Discurso 3 de Octubre de 1965, Himno del guerrillero
          Record Label: Egrem-MC, DP-SD-3
      - #243 Title: Carta del Che leda por Fidel
        - Performer: Fidel Castro (Box 49)
          Himno del guerrillero, Marcha de America Latina, Carta del Che leda por Fidel
          Record Label: Egrem, E-33
      - #244 Title: Versos sencillos: cantados por Oscar Chavez
        - Performer: Benjamin "Chamin" Correa, conductor (Box 49)
          La nia de Guatemala, Mi honda es la de David, La bailarina Espaola, Yo tengo un amigo muerto
          Record Label: Egrem (Casa de las Amricas), EP-CA-6
      - #245 Title: Canciones del grupo de experimentacin
        - Performer: Pablo Milans (Box 49)
          Pobre del cantor, Campesina
          Record Label: Areito, EPA-6405
      - #246 Title: Canciones revolucionarias
        - Performer: Carlos Puebla y Sus Tradicionales (Box 49)
          Y eso lleg fidel, Cinco puntos de la dignidad, Ya ganamos la pelea, La cuarentena
          Record Label: Areito, EPA-1008
      - #247 Title: Hasta siempre Comandante
        - Performer: Carlos Puebla (Box 49)
          Hasta siempre, Que pare el son, Lo eterno, Un nombre
          Record Label: Areito, EP.6107
      - #248 Title: 26 de Julio: Los nuevos heroes
        - Performer: Silvio Rodrguez, Pablo Milans, Noel Nicola (2 copies) (Box 49)
          Cancin del Eligido, 26, Moncada, Qu hay, Todo el mundo tiene su Moncada
          Record Label: Egrem (Casa de las Amricas)
      - #249 Title: Cancin protesta
        - Performer: Silvio Rodrguez, Pablo Milans (Box 49)
          La era est pariendo un corazon, Por qu, Su nombre puede ponerse en verso, Por la vida, Fusil contra fusil
          Record Label: Egrem (Casa de las Amricas), C.P. 2
    - France
      - #250 Title: A prsent, tu peux t'en aller (I Only Want to be With You); Rien que toi (You'll Never Walk Alone); coute dans le vent (Blowin' in the Wind), Elle a dit non (Loddy Lo)
        - Performer: Richard Anthony (Box 49)
          Record Label: Columbia, ESRF 1498
      - #251 Title: Mourir a Madrid: musique de Maurice Jarre
        - Performer: Bande originale du film de Frederic Rossif (Box 49)
          Mourir a Madrid, Coplas de la defensa de Madrid, El paso del ebro
          Record Label: Philips, 432 881 BE
      - #252 Title: Monthus
        - Performer: Christian Borel (Box 49)
          La vierge rouge, Gloire au 17, Le chant des jeunes gardes
          Record Label: BAM EX 616
      - #253 Title: Le grand testament
        - Performer: Bertha Bovy, Jean Deschamps (Box 49)
          Ballade pour prier Notre-Dame, Je plains le temps de ma jeunesse, Ballade des Dames du temps jadis, Mort, j'appelle de ta rigeur, Epitaphe, Ballade des pendus
          Record Label: L'Encyclopedie Sonore, 190 E 859
      - #254 Title: Chants de lutte
        - Performer: Les Camarades (Box 49)
          La chanson de craonne, L'Appel du komintern, Les survivants, Clairvaux
          Record Label: tudes et Documentation Internationales Cercle du Disque Socialiste, C.D.S. 1
      - #255 Title: Chants de lutte
        - Performer: Les Camarades (Box 49)
          L'Internationale, Ceux d'oviedo, Zimmerwald
          Record Label: tudes et Documentation Internationales Cercle du Disque Socialiste, C.D.S. 2
      - #256 Title: Chants de la libert franais
        - Performer: Chorale Populaire de Paris (Box 49)
          La Marseillaise, Les canuts, Ronde des Saint-Simoniens, Chant des combattants de la libert, Jeunesse
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, LDY - 4171
      - #257 Title: Chansons Bibliques - 2
        - Performer: A.M. Cocagnac O.P. (Box 49)
          Petit David prit trois cailloux, Zache, Chanaan, Les faces de Carme
          Record Label: Lumen, L D-I-117
      - #258 Title: La force de l'amour
        - Performer: Paul luard (Box 49)
          Le dit de la force de l'amour, Le 5 pome visible: Je vis dans les images innombrables, Je t'ai imagin, D'un et de deux, de tous, Avis
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, LD Y-6001
      - #259 Title: Potes d'aujourd'hui
        - Performer: Paul luard (Box 49)
          Couvre-feu, Je ne suis pas seul, Poesie ininterrompue, Notre vie, Printemps, Bonne justice, "La posie doit avoir pour but la vrit pratique"
          Record Label: Vega, P 37 A 4014
      - #260 Title: Mon accordon, Bombardiers, Dans le dsert glac, Revenir
        - Performer: Fania Fenelon (Box 49)
          Record Label: Eterna, 5 10 073
      - #261 Title: La Pegre
        - Performer: Dominique Grange (Box 49)
          Nous sommes tous, Grve illimite, Chacun de vous est concern, A bas l'etat policir
          Record Label: S 17 789
      - #262 Title: Jolie Mome, On n'oublie rien, C'etait bien, La famille dupanard
        - Performer: Juliette Greco (Box 49)
          Record Label: Philips, 432.552 BE
      - #263 Title: Sur le verbe aimer, La fte aux copains, Les canotiers, Le torrent et l'amour
        - Performer: Juliette Greco (Box 49)
          Record Label: Philips 432.753 BE
      - #264 Title: Le condamn a mort
        - Performer: Hlne Martin (Box 49)
          Fille de Jrusalem, Saint Ouen's blues, Trve
          Record Label: BAM, EX 614
      - #265 Title: Chansons d'hier et d'aujord'hui
        - Performer: Mouloudji (Box 49)
          Comme un p'tit coquelicot, La complainte des infideles, Si tu t'imagines, Le mal de Paris
          Record Label: Philips 432.114 BE
      - #266 Title: scrivains d'hier et d'aujourd'hui
        - Author: Pierre de Ronsard (Box 49)
        - Performer: Andr Reybaz (Box 49)
          Mignonne, allons voir...; La fontaine bellerie, Pren ceste rose aimable comme toi..., Marie levez-vous, ma jeune paresseuse...; Comme on voit sur la branche, Le premier jour de may, Hlne, je vous jure..., Je plante en ta faveur..., Quand vous serez bien vieille, Plus estroit que la vigne a l'ormeau se Marie, Il faut laisser maisons et vergers..., A son ame
          Record Label: Disques Vega, P 37 A 6002
      - #267 Title: Chanson de Petroulias
        - Performer: Mikis Theodorakis (Box 49)
          Extraits de l'Otage - 1. Celui qui souriait 2. Il n'est pas de lieu sur la terre
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, EP_45 3240
      - #268 Title: scrivains d'hier et d'aujourd'hui
        - Author: Franois Villon (Box 49)
        - Performer: Serge Reggiani (Box 49)
          Le lais, Ballade des dames du temps jadis, Ballade des pendus, Ballade des femmes de Paris, Mort, j'appelle de ta rigueur, Le Testament
          Record Label: Vega, P 37 A 6001
    - Germany
      - #269 Title: Chants revolutionaires allemands
        - Performer: Chorale de l'Union des Syndicats de Berlin, Gerhard Raeker, conductor (Box 49)
          Lied der Werktatigen, Die Moorsoldaten, Brueder, zur Sonne, zur Freiheit, Das Einheitsfrontlied, Die Thaelmannkolonne, Das Lied vom Kleinen Trompeter
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, LDY-4096
    - Greece
      - #270 Title: Atene in piazza, 1940-1965: canzoni della resistenza greca
        - Performer: Maria Faranduri, Olimpia Papadukas, P. Castagnino, Gruppo Celso di Genova, A. Celso, Retty Zalokostas, N. Teodosiadis (Box 49)
          Kato stu valtu, Vasi a duce ti stoli tu, Ston polemo vjeni o italos, Saranda pende petini, Canzone Sotiri Petrula, Manifestazioni popolari dell'agosto 1965 in piazza Sintagma ad Atene
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-51
    - Italy
      - #271 Title: Canti comunisti italiani
        - Performer: Fausto Amodei, Adriano Amedei, Michele L. Straniero, Sandra Mantovani (Box 49)
          La guardia rossa, Comune di Parigi, Noi siam la canaglia pezzente, O fucile, vecchio mio compagno, Siamo l'Emilia rossa, O cancellier che tieni la penna in mano
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-5
      - #272 Title: Uccidi e capirai (Serie Sperimentale)
        - Performer: Rudy Assuntino (Box 49)
          Rossa provvidenza (Le basi americane), Canzone del mondo, Nostro Messico, L'uomo che sa, Autunno '65
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-52
      - #273 Title: 'Sta bruta guera che no xe fina
        - Performer: Gualtiero Bertelli (Box 49)
          Ma 'sti signori, Ae case minime, Balada del carovita, I do piovani, Alle 14,30
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-42
      - #274 Title: Vedrai com' bello
        - Performer: Gualtiero Bertelli (Box 49)
          Vedrai com' bello, Gli ingranaggi
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-206
      - #275 Title: Bella ciao
        - Performer: Xesc Boix (Box 49)
          Koll doo d, Ei! Ei!, Meu Manuel, Vull ser lliure
          Record Label: Ais 4 Vents, A4V-7
      - #276 Title: Canzoni dal carcere 2
        - Performer: Caterina Bueno, Giovanna Marini Salviucci, Giuseppe Ganduscio (Box 49)
          Il mastio di Vorterra, La canzone di Portolongone, A ttcchi, a ttcchi la campana sona, E 'nta la Vicaria
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-47
      - #277 Title: I canti del lavoro 2 (Serie canti politici e sociali)
        - Performer: Giovanna Daffini Carpi, Giuseppe Ganduscio, Sandra Mantovani, P.F., Gruppo di cavatori di marmo di Carrara (Box 49)
          Amore mio non piangere, Mamma mia dammi centro lire, canto ritmico dei cavatori di marmo, Caltanisetta fa quattru quarteri, E vaiu e vegnu di lu Mazzarinu, Povre filandere, La filanda de Ghisalba
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-10
      - #278 Title: I canti del lavoro 3 (Serie Canti politici e sociali) (Box 50)
        - Performer: Giovanna Daffini Carpi, Caterina Bueno, Giuseppe Ganduscio, Grupo Padano di Pidena, Adelaide Bona, Giovanna Marini Salviucci (Box 50)
          Sciur Padrun da li bli braghi bianchi; C sutta di stu 'nfernu; La Santa Caterina dei pastai; Tutti mi dicon Maremma, Maremma; A la matin' bonora; Addio, addio
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-29
      - #279 Title: Ballo tondo del Vietnam
        - Performer: Galletto di Gallura (Box 50)
          Noi lo chiamiamo Vietnam
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-204
      - #280 Title: Canti di protesta del popolo Italiano - 2
        - Performer: Margherita Galante Garrone, Fausto Amodei, Anna Bertolina, Trino Vercellese, Michele L. Straniero (Box 50)
          Il prigioniero, Inno della rivolta, Grizia, Il canto delle tessitrici, Inno individualista, Le otto ore
          Record Label: Italia Canta, SP33/R/0013
      - #281 Title: Canti di protesta del popolo italiano - 3
        - Performer: Margherita Galante Garrone, Giuliano Ferreio, Fausto Amodei, Tina Perrone (Box 50)
          Stornelli d'esilio, Ma la vita, Amore ribelle, Inno dell' albero, O cara mamma
          Record Label: Italia Canta, SP33/R/0017
      - #282 Title: La legge del padrone (Serie Sperimentale)
        - Performer: Gruppo Padano di Pidena (Box 50)
          Santa Caterina dei pastai, La campagnola, Il padrone socialista, Sciopero!
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-33
      - #283 Title: Canti aztechi
        - Performer: Alberto Lupo (Box 50)
          Canto di tristezza, Soltanto per poco, Solitario come nebbia, Canto di tetlepanquetzanitzin, Come erba di primavera, Canto dell'amicizia, Origine dei canti, Lamento del poeta, Canto d'esortazione per il guerriero, Un breve istante, Il dubbio, Almeno i fiori
          Record Label: Cetra - Collana Letteraria Documento, CL 0514 Mec. 4431
      - #284 Title: Canti e inni socialisti
        - Performer: Sandra Mantovani, Salsomaggiore Terme (Box 50)
          La boje!, Il canto dei lavoratori, Son cieco, L'Internazionale, E per la strada, Bandiera rossa, Povero Matteotti
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-3
      - #285 Title: La linea rossa, Ci che voi non dite
        - Performer: Giovanna Marini, Ivan Della Mea (Box 50)
          Record Label: Linea Rossa, LR 45/3-B
      - #286 Title: Io ti chiedo di fare l'amore, O cara moglie
        - Performer: Ivan Della Mea (Box 50)
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS 205/A
      - #287 Title: Canti comunisti italiani 2
        - Performer: Ivan Della Mea, Leonello Rambelli di Alfonsine (Ravenna), Rudy Assuntino, Rina Varotto di Bagnoli di sopra (Padova), Maria Monti, Fausto Amodei (Box 50)
          Quattro signori, La leggenda della Neva, Canzone d'Albania, Le tre bandiere, Vi ricordate quel 18 Aprile, Per i morti di Reggio Emilia
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-12
      - #288 Title: Ho letto sul giornale (Serie Sperimentale)
        - Performer: Ivan Della Mea (Box 50)
          La cansun del desperaa, Con la lettera del prete, Se il cielo fosse bianco di carta, Congo (Ballata di Stanleyville)
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-36
      - #289 Title: La mia vita ormai, Nove maggio, Ho saputo dagli occhi, A quel omm, Questa una storia
        - Performer: Ivan Della Mea, Sandra Mantovani (Box 50)
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-43
      - #290 Title: Milly 1 (Cabaret all'italiana)
        - Performer: Milly (Box 50)
          L'uomo e' fumator, T'ha detto niente la tua mammina, Come pioveva, Sono tre parole
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, Disc 1: DS-48
      - #291 Title: Milly 2 (Cabaret all'italiana)
        - Performer: Milly (Box 50)
          Jenny dei pirati, Ricordo di Cesare Pavese, Salomon song, Chanson dans le sang
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-27
      - #292 Title: Amore dammi quel fazzolettino, Bella ciao
        - Performer: Yves Montand (Box 50)
          Record Label: Philips, 373 252 BF
      - #293 Title: Le canzoni del no
        - Performer: Maria Monti (Box 50)
          Inno abissino, La ninna-nanna della guerra, Stronzio 90, La marcia della pace
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-24
      - #294 Title: Le canzoni del no
        - Performer: Gianni Morandi (Box 50)
          Title: C'era un ragazzo che come me amava i Beatles e i Rolling Stones, Se perdo anche te
          Record Label: RCA Italiana, PM45 3375
      - #295 Title: Canti per noi
        - Performer: Margot e Silverio Pisu (Box 50)
          Canzone dei fiori e del silenzio, Polesine, Il venditore di ventagli, Le deserteur, Il convento delle nazarene, Valzer della credulit
          Record Label: Di-enne-gi Edizioni Discografiche, gep 80009
      - #296 Title: La poesia civile della Resistenza
        - Performer: Salvatore Quasimodo (Box 50)
          Alle fronde dei salici, Ai fratelli cervi, alla loro Italia, Il mio paese l' Italia, Laude, Ai quindici di piazzale Loreto, Auschwitz, Epigrafe per i caduti di Marzabotto, Epigrafe per i partigiani di Valenza, Ancora dell'inferno
          Record Label: Edizioni Discografiche, GEP 80005
      - #297 Title: La revolution, Preghiera del marine
        - Performer: Michele Straniero (Box 50)
          Record Label: Linea Rossa, LR 45/6
      - #298 Title: Proposte per Milly
        - Performer: Nanni Svampa Giampeiro, Borella Nuccio Ambrosino, Ivan Della Mea (Box 50)
          Si pu morire, Valige di cartone, Quand gh'avevi sedes ann, L'era alegra tutt i d
          Record Label: Dischi del Sole, DS-30
      - #299 Title: Dans la clandestinit
        - Performer: Mikis Theodorakis (Box 50)
          Dans la clandestinit, chante la lutte du peuple grec, Contre le fascisme
          Record Label: Clart en collaboration avec La Jeunesse Lambrakis, SF 9-7-117
      - #300 Title: (Mille) Chitarre contro la guerra
        - Performer: Carmen Villiani (Box 50)
          Chitarre contro la guerra, Ti prego resta accanto a me
          Record Label: Bluebell Record, BB 03161
    - Mexico
      - #301 Title: Chants mexicains
        - Performer: Los Guarachos (Box 50)
          Malaguea, Las canastas, Rosita Alvirez, La cama de piedra
          Record Label: Riviera, 231 055 M
      - #302 Title: El corrido de Deleno, Carta de un soldado
        - Performer: Lalo Guerrero con el Conjunto Arellano (Box 50)
          Record Label: Colonial Discos Latinos, 537 CR-979/980
      - #303 Title: Camino Real de Colima, El hidalguense, El maracumb, Las copetonas
        - Performer: El Mariachi Vargas de Tecalitlan (Box 50)
          Record Label: RCA Victor, MKE 135
      - #304 Title: Cantares, Las moscas, Llanto y coplas, La saeta
        - Performer: Joan Manuel Serrat (Box 50)
          Record Label: Capitol, EPEM 10366
      - #305 Title: La malaguea, Flor silvestre, Cielito lindo, Dos arbolitos
        - Performer: Trio Calaveras: Miguel Bermejo, Ral Prado, Jos Saldivar (Box 50)
          Record Label: RCA Victor, MKE 18 A
      - #306 Title: Me voy p'al pueblo, Flor de azalea, Ya es muy tarde, Canta morena
        - Performer: Trio Los Panchos: Gil, Navarro, Aviles, Vol. 4 (Box 50)
          Record Label: Columbia, EPC 48
    - Nicaragua
      - #307 Title: Nicaragua vencer
        - Performer: Oscar Chavez (Box 50)
          Ya cay Somoza!, Caballo Crillo
          Record Label: Polygram Polydor 2467 2219075
    - Peru
      - #308 Title: Canto coral a Tupac Amaru, Tupaqamaruman ukhuti takina taki
        - Performer: Alejandro Romualdo (Box 50)
          Record Label: Smith, 002 No. 4394
    - Spain
      - #309 Title: Cinco caballos moros, A la divina clemencia, Ay, seorona!, Cllate la boca!
        - Performer: Nia de Antequera (Box 50)
          Record Label: Columbia, ECGE 71365
      - #310 Title: Canti popolari di Spagna
        - Performer: Julian Grimau hermanos, Coplas, Los dos gallos, Paloma de la Paz (Box 50)
          Record Label: Italia Canta, SP 33/CRA/0034
      - #311 Title: Ritmos y cantos de Espaa
        - Performer: Luis Maravilla, Pepe Valencia (Box 50)
          Farruca, Bulerias, Souvenirs de l'Alhambra, Jota, Seguriyas, Aires gallegos
          Record Label: Ducretet-Thomson, LPP 8602
      - #312 Title: Paseando por Espaa: Chansons populaires d'Espagne
        - Performer: Germaine Montero (Box 50)
          Gallegada, Folia de San Vicente de la Barquera, Asturiana, Paso Rio, Eres alta y delgada, No hay quien pueda, Jotas, El baile de Avila, Corrocloclo, Ya se van los pastores, Con las abejas, Los cuatro muleros, Los contrabandistas de ronda
          Record Label: Le Chant du Monde, LDY-M-4006
      - #313 Title: El 13 de mar, Can dels creients; Indesinenter; Sobre la pau, Sobre la por
        - Performer: Raimon (Box 50)
          Record Label: Discophon INICI, 27.545
      - #314 Title: Canto a Manolete, Que bonita que es mi nia, Mi barca no tiene vela, Que buena soy
        - Performer: Gracia de Triana (Box 50)
          Record Label: Philips, 421 225 PE
    - United States
      - #315 Title: In the 80's (Watchu Gonna Do)
        - Performer: The May Day Singers (Box 50)
          Five Alive
          Record Label: Blackbeard Records, CWP 1980B
      - #316 Title: X-Mas Bells, Shook-Up Santy (Box 50)
        Record Label: Reeves Soundcraft Corp.